AJAYSINH SOLANKI

∥ Cell: 9427450518 ∥ ajaysolanki225@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Team-oriented Mechanical **Engineer** with more than 1 year of progressive experience specializing in teaching field (lecturer) and 4 year of progressive experience specializing in **sales and service Engineer**. Since 2020 to till today I am working in a same field. Now I am looking a position for my stable future. Where who works effectively with all levels of areas.

HIGHLIGHTS

- Sales & service engineer in South Gujarat for Shree Ganesh Steel.
- Sales & service engineer in Gujarat, Rajasthan, M.P. (west india) for Dynacorp Engineering.
- Oil management System installation
- Engineering AMC works
- Quality Improvement Techniques
- Good communicator with fluency in English, Hindi, Gujarati, languages.
- Analytical problem solver
- Work force management
- Active Learner, Listener
- Coordination
- Adept multi-task
- Deal with the customer with standardization rate

EXPERIENCE

- Sales and Service Engineer Shree Ganesh Steel
- GPSC aspirant and lecturer in same field
- Sales and Service Engineer
 Dynacorp Engineering Pvt. Ltd.
 (ORION lube management system, sweden)
- As a Lecturer

03/01/2020 to till today Ankleshwar, Gujarat 2016 to 2020

10/08/2015 to 11/08/2016 Nashik, Maharashtara

10/06/2013 to 03/01/2014

Sales Activities for Shree Ganesh Steel

- Observing South Gujarat to deal with the customer about Industrial Materials like Ferrous and Non- Ferrous metal, s.s. materials, Flanges, Copper Filler wire, Brass Aluminum etc. Responsible for ensuring that the find customer with our knowledge.
- Quality Review Meetings with the customer.
- Perform all internal audits on behalf of the company's management.
- It also includes regular contact and deals with vendors regarding requirement, rate negotiation and finalization of rate.

Sales Activities for Dynacorp Engineering

- Observing western region basically Gujarat, Rajasthan and M.P. to deal with the customer according to Oil management system in industries and workshops. (ORION LUB MANAGEMENT SYSTEM, SWIDEN).
- Organizing Educational training program for workers to improve their skills.
- Guide to company management for product feedback and improvement in Standardization.

Service Activities for Shree Ganesh Steel

- Visit industries and workshops where the material uses. Understanding all the requirements of customers which material will be prefers them.
- Give the technical advice about the material to the co-workers.

Service Activities for Dynacorp Engineering.

- Completes drawing a plane layout for installation.
- Installation all the System by my best of knowledge with software use.
- Annual Maintenance contract (AMC) work is maintaining by monitoring steps of
 process, setting processing variables, observing control points and equipments,
 monitoring personnel and resources, study methods, developing reporting procedure
 and systems.
- Installed error free system to reduce non productive time.
- Supervising the work of junior staff.
- Maintains safe and clean work environment by educating and directing personnel on the use of all control points and equipments.
- Maintains professional and technical knowledge by attending educational workshops and by use of internets.
- Contributes efforts by accomplishing related results as needed.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering: - Mechanical Engineering

2012 with 1st Class (60.47%)

Veer Narmad South Gujarat University, Surat, Gujarat.

Bharuch, Gujarat, India

HSC (Gujarat Board): - Science

2006 with 1st Class (62.20%)

GUJCET Entrance Exam Score: - 46.60 % Board Highest in Mathematics M&M MEHTA HIGHSCHOOL,

Godhra, Gujarat, India

Devgadh baria, Gujarat, India

AFFILIATIONS

- I have undergone a training program in turbine maintenance department and boiler maintenance department at the leading power Generation Company of Gujarat WANAKBORI THERMAL POWER STATION Dist.Kheda.Gujarat.
- I had also industrial visit of Wellspune (Dahej) and Alang (Bhavnagar) Ship breaking yard.

• PROJECT SUMMARY:

SUBJECT: FABRICATION & PERFORMANCE OF HEAT EXCHANGER

I am working with heat exchanger in project work. In this project I have briefly analysis the heat exchanger and its parts. Uses of two heat exchanger.

- 1. Single tube heat exchanger
- 2. Shell & tube heat exchanger

I have done fabrication of both heat exchanger in one model. After this I have perform the experiment by using water and oil as cold &hot fluid respectively. Then calculate effectiveness of both heat exchanger simultaneously. By keeping constant mass flow rate using trial & error method.

This system that we are developing is use full to know more effectiveness for company and students practical work.

	PERSONAL DETAILS
• Name	: AJAYSINH VIRENDRASINH SOLANKI
• Address	: Navaghara Gayatrinagar, At and Post :Bahi ,
 Nationality 	Ta.: Shahera, Dist.: Panchmahal. Gujarat 389001. : Indian
Gender	: Male
 Date of birth 	: 5 May 1989
 Marital Status 	: Unmarried
 Languages known 	: English, Hindi, Gujarati

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.